[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
Morty, you got to come on.
You got to come with me.
What's going on?
I got a surprise for you, Morty.
It's the middle of the night.
I got a surprise for you.
Ow! You're tugging me too hard.
I got a surprise for you, Morty.
What do you… [BURPS] What do you
think of this flying vehicle, Morty?
I built it out of stuff I
found in the garage.
Yeah, Rick, it's… it's great.
Is this the surprise?
Morty, I had to… I had to do…
I had to… I had to…
I had to make a bomb, Morty.
I had to create a bomb.
What?! A bomb?!
We're gonna drop it down there…
Just get a whole fresh start, Morty.
Create a whole fresh start.
Th… Th… That's absolutely crazy!
Come on, Morty. Just take it easy, Morty.
It's gonna be good.
Right now, we're gonna go
pick up your little friend Jessica.
Jessica?
From my math class?
When I drop the bomb, I don't…
You know, I want you to have somebody,
you know… I want you to have the thing…
I'm gonna make it like
a new Adam and Eve,
and you're gonna be Adam.
[GROANS]
And Jessica's gonna be Eve,
and so that's the surprise, Morty.
No, you can't!
Je… Jessica doesn't even know I exist.
But… But… But forget about that,
because you can't blow up humanity.
I… I get what you're
trying to say, Mo… Morty.
Listen, I'm not… you don't…
Yo… Yo… You don't got to worry about
me trying to fool around with…
With Jessica or mess around
with Jessica or anything.
I'm… I'm not that kind of guy, Morty.
What are you talking about, Rick?
You… You…
You don't have to worry about me getting
with Jessica or anything.
She… She… She's all for you, Morty.
I don't care about Jessica!
You know what, Morty? You're right.
Let's forget the girl all together.
She… She's probably
nothing but trouble, anyways.
SHIP: Arming Neutrino bomb.
That's it… That's it, Rick.
I'm taking the wheel.
Get off of me, Morty!
I'm taking charge of
this situation, buddy.
What's gotten into you?
I'm… I'm… I'm…
I'm not gonna stand around
like some sort of dumb…
What are you, crazy?
…person and just let you
blow up the whole world.
All right, all right.
I'll… I'll land.
I'll land. I'll land.
I'll land the thing.
Big tough guy all of a sudden.
We'll park it right here, Morty.
Right here on the
si… side of the ro… road here.
Oh, thank God.
You know what?
That was all a test, Morty.
Just an elaborate test to
make you more assertive.
It was?
Sure. Why not?
I don't… I don't know.
You… You know what, Mor… [SNORING]
SHIP: Neutrino bomb armed.
[BEEPING]
-Um…
-[BEEPING INCREASES]
I see there's a new episode
of that singing show tonight.
Who do you guys think is
gonna be the best singer?
Oh, my God. His head is in his food.
I'm going to puke.
Morty, are you getting sick?
I told you not to practice-kiss
the living-room pillow.
The dog sleeps on it.
I wasn't kissing a pillow, Mom.
I just…
I didn't get a lot of sleep last night.
Maybe my dreams were
just too loud or something.
Or maybe you were out all
night again with Grandpa Rick.
What?!
Dad?
What, so everyone's supposed
to sleep every single night now?
You realize that nighttime
makes up half of all time?
Damn it!
-Jerry!
-Beth!
Oh, my God. My parents are so loud.
I want to die.
Mm, there is no God, Summer.
You got to rip that Band-Aid off now.
You'll thank me later.
Okay, with all due respect, Rick…
What am I talking about?
What respect is due?
How is my son supposed to pass
his classes if you keep dragging
him off for high-concept
sci-fi rigamarole?
Listen, Jerry, I… I don't want to
overstep my bounds or anything.
It's your house. It's your world.
You're a real Julius Caesar.
But I'll tell you some… Tell you how…
How I feel about school, Jerry.
It's a waste of time…
A bunch of people running around,
bumping into each other.
Gu… Guy up front says, "Two plus two."
The people in the back say, "Four."
Then the bell rings, and
they give you a carton of milk
and a piece of paper that says you
can go take a dump or something.
I mean, it's…
it's not a place for smart people, Jerry.
And I know that's not a popular opinion,
but it's my two cents on the issue.
This was a good breakfast, Beth.
You really made the
crap out of those eggs.
I wish your mother was here to eat them.
Oh, Dad.
What?
For real?
TEACHER: All right,
now, everybody get settled.
Get away from the windows!
Now, look, we're gonna be
dealing with some
real serious stuff today.
You might have heard of it.
It's called math.
And without it, none
of us would even exist,
so let's jump right in… Two plus two.
Jessica.
Five plus five.
Tenssica.
Okay, good.
It's time for the quiz.
[ALL GROAN]
Yeah, you know what?! Aw, too bad!
Tough!
First row, take one. Pass it back for me.
The stakes are high in this room.
There's crucial things
happening here every day.
People getting smarter.
Some of y'all getting dumber.
Some of y'all ain't
gonna see three o'clock.
JESSICA: Hi, Morty.
Whoa!
Hi, Jessica.
Can I show these to you?
Wow.
Th… They're both great.
Thank you.
You know what I named these?
My little Morties.
Uh, that's flattering…
and a little weird.
Do you know what I
want you to do with them?
Rename them?
Squeeze them.
Manhandle them.
Give them the business.
See if you can shuffle them.
I mean, really get in there
and knock them around.
No wrong answers.
Wow.
Well, okay, Jessica.
Le… Let's give this a shot.
Mm.
Oh, Morty.
What are you doing to me?
Uh, I… I'm just doing my best.
Morty!
What are you doing to me?!
Jessica.
Morty!
[MUMBLING] Jessica.
Five more minutes of this,
and I'm gonna get mad.
Je… Jessica.
[MUMBLING] Jessica.
Not my fault this is happening.
[SCHOOL BELL RINGS]
Well, well, well.
Uh, morning, Frank.
"Morning"?
What was… What is that supposed to mean?
You making fun of me?
Are you trying to say my family's poor?
Oh, jeez, Frank.
I don't know if a knife is necessary.
I mean, you know, yo… you kind
of had things handled without it.
You telling me how to bully now?
Big mistake, Morty.
And now I'm gonna cut
you, 'cause my family's rich.
[GASPS]
There you are, Morty.
Listen to me.
I got an errand to run in a
whole different dimension.
I need an extra pair of hands.
Oh, jeez, Rick.
Wh… What'd you do to Frank?
It's pretty obvious, Morty. I froze him.
Now listen… I need your help, Morty.
I mean, we got… we got to get…
Get the hell out of here
and go take care of business.
[BURPS]
It's important. Come on, Morty.
I don't know, Rick.
I… I can't leave school again.
Do you have any concept of
how much higher the stakes
get out there, Morty?
What do you think…
I can just do it all by myself?
Come on!
Aw, jeez. Okay.
I guess I can skip History.
What about Frank?
I mean, shouldn't you unfreeze him?
I'll do it later, Morty.
He'll be fine.
Let's go.
[THINKING] Oh, my God.
I'm about to walk past Frank Palicky.
This is the story we'll
be telling our children.
Hi, Frank.
[CRACKS, SHATTERS]
Aah!
[HORSE WHINNYING]
Scalpel.
-[DOOR OPENS]
-Knock, knock.
Jerry?
My manager gave me an
hour for lunch, and I thought,
"Hey, why not swing by
where your wife works?"
-[FLATLINE]
-We're losing him.
-[BEEPS]
-Okay, he's back.
Jerry, please tell me you're here
for an incredibly urgent reason.
Well, it's lunch.
I mean, it's one of three meals
that have existed for millennia.
-[FLATLINE]
-Losing him.
-[BEEPS]
-Stabilized.
Okay, I only ask, Jerry,
because, as you know,
my job involves performing heart surgery.
[SOFTLY] Well, yeah, on horses.
Excuse me?
Okay. Let's not rehash that fight.
I sense that you're busy
and will now be on my way.
Whoa!
What is this on the floor?
Some kind of literature for a
really nice-looking nursing home.
Hey, honey, crazy idea… Bad pitch…
Let's put your dad here.
Let's put your dad in a nursing home.
[FLATLINE]
We're losing him.
Hey, Tom.
We know when we're losing him.
We can hear the beeps!
There she is. All right.
Come on, Morty. Let's go.
Oh, jeez.
Okay.
Oh, man, Rick.
What is this place?
It's dimension 35C,
and it's got the perfect
climate conditions for a
special type of tree, Morty,
called a Mega tree,
and there's fruit in those trees,
and there's seeds in those fruits.
I'm talking about Mega seeds.
They're…
[BURPING] They're incredibly powerful,
and I need them to help
me with my research, Morty.
Oh, man, Rick.
I'm looking around this place,
and I'm starting to work up some
anxiety about this whole thing.
All right. All right. Calm down.
Listen to me, Morty.
I know that new situations
can be intimidating.
You're looking around, and
it's all scary and different, but,
you know, me… meeting them
head on, charging right into them
like a bull…
That's how we grow as people.
I'm no stranger to scary situations.
I deal with them all the time.
Now, if you just stick with
me, Morty, we're gonna be…
Holy crap, Morty, run!
[SCREAMING]
I never seen that
thing before in my life.
I don't even know what the hell it is!
We got to get out of here, Morty!
It's gonna kill us!
We're gonna die!
We're gonna die, Morty!
Oh, Morty, take a deep breath.
Breathe that…
Breathe that fresh air in, Morty.
Yo… You smell that?
That's the smell of adventure, Morty.
That's… That's the smell of…
of… of a whole different
evolutionary timeline.
All right, Rick, look…
How much longer is this gonna be?
Shouldn't I be back at school by now?
Are you joking me?
I mean, look at all the
crazy crap surrounding us.
Look at that thing right there.
Wh… What the hell is that thing?
You think you're gonna see
that kind of thing at school?
Look at it just lumbering around.
It defies all logic… That thing.
Yeah, Rick, I get it.
We're surrounded by monsters.
That's kind of the reason
why I want to leave.
Ta-ta-ta-ta-ta-ta.
-Morty, you see this?
-[ANGELIC CHORDS PLAY]
You see what we just
stumbled upon, Morty?
Any idea what that is down there?
The Mega trees?
That's right, Morty… The Mega trees
with the Mega fruit on them.
And that's what I'm talking about, Morty.
That's where my seeds are.
If we would have done what you wanted,
I would have never have found them,
because yo…
because you're so in love with school.
All right, all right.
So, what's so special
about these seeds, anyways?
You ask a lot of questions, Morty.
Not very charismatic.
It makes you kind of an [BURPS] under
[BURPS] underfoot figure.
Just take these shoes, Morty.
They're sp…
[BURPS] special grappling shoes.
When you're wearing these things…
ba… these babies,
you can basically just walk on
any surface you want, Morty…
Up, down, below, turn around to the left.
These things really
bring it all together.
[YELLS]
You have to turn them on, Morty!
[THUDS]
The shoes have to be turned on!
BETH: I am not putting
my father in a home!
He just came back into my life,
and you want to grab him and
stuff him under a mattress like
last month's Victoria's Secret?
I told you… I was ordering you
something for Valentine's Day.
More importantly, your father is
a horrible influence on our son.
Everything cool in here, Beth?
It's fine, Davin.
Okay, cool.
You know, we did something great today.
There's nothing more noble
and free than the heart of a horse.
Since we're fighting, if
you ever have an affair
with that guy, I will
come to the hotel room
and blow my brains out
all over your naked bodies.
Look, I appreciate the
stress you're under, but
Morty was having trouble in
school way before my dad moved
in, and the only influence I
can see Rick having is that,
for the first time in his
life, Morty has a friend.
[TELEPHONE RINGING]
[SIGHS]
Well, maybe you're right.
Uh, yeah, maybe I am.
I'm my father's daughter.
I'm smart.
Why do you think I'm a heart surgeon?
Horse heart surgeon.
-Hello?
-Mrs. Smith?
This is Principal Vagina… No relation.
I wonder if you and Morty's
father might be able to have
a chat with me this afternoon?
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYS]
Morty, oh, you really di… did a
number on your legs right now.
[GROANING]
You know, you got to
turn the shoes on, Morty,
for them to work.
Yeah, look… I turned mine on.
I had no problem getting down here.
It was a leisurely breeze.
I'm in a lot of pain, Rick.
Yeah, I can see that.
But do you think you'll still be
able to help me [BURPS] collect
my seeds, Morty?
Are you kidding me?!
That's it, Rick!
That's the last straw!
I can't believe this…
I'm sitting here with both
of my legs broken, and
you're still asking me
about getting those seeds?!
Ooh! Ow! Oh!
Yo… Yo… You're a monster.
Yo… You're like Hitler, but…
But even Hitler cared
about Germany or something.
Okay, hold on just a second, Morty.
[GROANING]
[PANTING]
Ooh.
Ohh.
Wow, Rick.
That stuff just healed
my broken legs instantly.
I mean, I've never
felt so good in my life.
Thank you.
Don't worry about it, Morty.
Just come help me get
these seeds, all right, buddy?
Sure thing, Rick.
Not that you asked, Morty,
but what just happened
there is I went into a future
dimension with such advanced
medicine that they had
broken-leg serum at every
corner drugstore.
The stuff was all over the place, Morty.
Wow, that's pretty crazy, Rick.
There's just one problem, Morty…
One little hang-up.
The dimension I visited was so advanced,
they had also halted the aging process,
and everyone there was young, Morty,
and they had been forever.
I was the only old person there, Morty.
It was [BURPS] like I was
some sort of, you know, celebrity,
walking around.
I… I was fascinating to them.
There were a lot of attractive
women there, Morty, and they…
They… They… They all wanted time with me.
I had a lot of fun with
a lot of young ladies,
but I spent so much time there,
my interdimensional portal device…
It's got no charge left, Morty.
It's got no charge left.
What?!
It's as good as garbage, Morty.
It's not gonna work anymore, Morty.
Oh, jeez, Rick, that's not good.
Wh… What are we gonna do?
I… I have to be back at school right now.
How are we gonna get back home?
There's ways to get back home, Morty.
It's just… It's just gonna
be a little bit of a hassle.
We're gonna have to go
through interdimensional customs,
so you're gonna have
to do me a real solid.
Uh-oh.
When we get to Customs,
I'm gonna need you to take
these seeds into the bathroom,
and I'm gonna need you to put them way up
inside your butthole, Morty.
In my butt?
Put them way up inside
there, as far as they can fit.
Oh, jeez, Rick.
I really don't want to have to do that.
Well, somebody's got to do it, Morty.
Th… These seeds aren't gonna
get through Customs unless they're
in someone's rectum, Morty.
[WHIMPERS]
And they'll fall right out of mine.
I've done this too many times, Morty.
I mean, you're young.
You've got your whole life ahead of you,
and your anal cavity is
still taut, yet malleable.
You got to do it for Grandpa, Morty.
Yo… You've got to put these
seeds inside your butt.
In my butt?
Come on, Morty.
Please, Morty.
You have to do it, Morty.
Oh, man.
[SCHOOL BELL RINGS]
PRINCIPAL: The fact is, your son,
Morty, has attended this school for a
total of seven hours
over the last two months.
What? Why didn't you notify us?
I done been notifying you.
Have you not been getting the messages
I've been leaving with
Morty's grandfather?
Boom!
Told you! In your face!
He is ruining our child!
Wait, what am I celebrating?
Yeah, see, I thought
something was fishy there,
because it's usually
Morty's grandpa that's taking
him out of school.
Summer?
[SOBBING] What kind
of God lets this happen?
We had a little incident.
A student was frozen to death.
And there's no evidence
that a Latino student did it!
Everyone wants to
take this to a racial place.
I won't let them.
The Glarp Zone is for
flarping and unglarping only.
ALIEN: So, I told him, "Give
me the Blimfarx," you know?
This… This guy…
He doesn't understand
interstellar currency.
It's, like, I'm trying to eat a Flimflam…
Like, that's what we eat on Girvonesk.
The glarp zone is for
flarping and unglarping only.
I don't like it here, Morty.
I can't abide bureaucracy.
I don't like being told
where to go and what to do.
I consider it a violation.
Did you get those seeds
all the way up your butt?
Yeah, Rick.
Let's just get this over with, okay?
I mean, these things are pointy.
They hurt.
That means they're good ones.
You're a good kid, Morty.
Those Mega seeds are
super valuable to my work.
You've been a huge help to me.
I'm gonna be able to do [BURPS]
all kinds of things with them.
It's gonna be great, Morty.
[BURPS] All kinds of science.
Okay, next through.
Except you. You go over there.
Why does he have to go over there?
Random check.
He's got to go through the new machine.
What new… [BURPS] What new machine?
It's a new machine.
It detects stuff all
the way up your butt.
Run, Morty! Run!
Aah!
Red alert!
[ALARMS BLARING]
[GRUNTS]
[SCREECHING]
Ohhh!
[COUGHS]
[CRYING]
[COUGHING]
Hey! Ohhh.
[GROANS]
Aah!
Don't think about it!
Ooh!
[SHOES BEEPING]
Oh, nice, Morty!
The student becomes the teacher.
[BUZZING]
[BOTH SCREAMING]
[BOTH GRUNT]
Whooo!
Aah!
Aw, hell, no, dawg.
-You know me… I'm just trying to…
-Aah!
I need to type in the coordinates
to our home world, Morty.
-Cover me.
-Oh, man.
I mean, you know, I… I
don't want to shoot nobody.
They're just robots, Morty!
It's okay to shoot them!
They're robots!
Aah!
My leg is shot off!
Glenn's bleeding to death!
Someone call his wife and children!
They're not robots, Rick!
It's a figure of speech, Morty.
They're bureaucrats.
I don't respect them.
Just keep shooting, Morty.
You have no idea
what prison is like here!
Holy crap! This is insane!
[CROWD SCREAMING]
RICK: Come on, Morty!
We got to get the hell out of here!
[ALL GASP]
Wow.
Did you just come into the
cafeteria through a portal?
Uh, yeah.
Well, you know, my…
my Ferrari's in the shop.
[CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY]
Ju… Just kidding.
-You're Morty, right?
-Yeah.
You can get his number later.
Come on, Morty.
We got to get out of here.
You got to get those
seeds out of your ass.
Oh, look, honey.
It's our son with Albert Ein-douche.
What?
I'm an angry father, not an improvisor.
Oh, hi, Jerry.
Oh, my goodness, Morty!
What are you doing out of class?
We talked about this.
Your… Your parents and I
are very disappointed in…
In this behavior.
No? No takers?
You guys should really
not be touching that stuff.
It's beyond your reasoning.
You're beyond our reasoning!
Takes one to know one.
Dad, how could you make my son
miss an entire semester of school?
I mean, it's not like he's a hot girl.
He can't just bail on
his life and set up shop
in someone else's.
What…
What are you guys doing with my stuff?
We're moving you… to a nursing home.
A nursing home?
What are… What are you, nuts?
I'm a genius.
I build robots for fun.
Well, now you can build baskets
and watch Paul Newman movies
on VHS and mentally scar
the Boy Scouts every Christmas.
What does that mean?
It's personal.
Dad, Mom, co… come on.
Rick just needed my help is all.
Morty, stay out of this.
You are obviously not capable of
judging these situations on your own.
What are you trying to say about Morty?
That he's stupid or something?
Oh, don't high-road us, Dad.
You know fully well that Morty
is the last child that needs to
be missing classes.
I… I… I don't know what you mean by that.
Can… Can…
Can you be a little bit more specific?
Oh, for crying out…
He's got some kind of
disability or something.
Is that what you want us to say?
I do?
Well, duh doy, son.
Look, I love you, Morty, but we
both know you're not as fast as
the other kids, and if you
want to compete in this world,
you got to work twice as hard.
Aw, jeez, Dad.
Yo… You know, that's a lot
to drop on a kid all at once.
Morty, te… tell your parents
the square root of Pi.
Oh, come on, Rick.
You know I can't.
The square root of Pi, Morty… go.
1.77245385.
Whoa!
What the hell?
Holy crap. He's right.
Morty, tell your parents
the first Law of [BURPS]
thermodynamics.
"The increment in the internal
energy of a system is equal to
the increment of heat
supplied to the system."
Wow! I'm so smart!
But… I told the both of you…
School is stupid.
It's not how you learn things.
Morty's a gifted child.
He has a special mind.
That's why he's my little helper.
He's like me.
He's gonna be doing great
science stuff later in his life.
He's too smart for school.
He… He needs to keep hanging
out [BURPS] and helping me.
Jerry, I don't want whatever's
happening here to stop.
No, I… I understand.
Uh, maybe we overreacted.
But he has to keep going to school.
Okay, Jerry.
You drive a hard bargain,
but [BURPS] what am I supposed to do?
Say… [BURPS] Say no?
You… [BURPS] You really
wear the pants around here.
I just want you to know,
between us, from now on,
it's gonna be 100% honesty and open,
clear communication.
Frank Palicky was frozen to death today!
No idea what you're talking about.
[SOBBING]
Okay.
Well, uh, Morty, it's
your bedtime in an hour.
Don't stay up all night again.
This is good, though.
This can work.
I think we can be a family.
And now, Beth, if you'll have me,
I would love to have you.
You know what?
Okay.
Holy cow, Rick.
I didn't know hanging out with
you was making me smarter.
Full disclosure, Morty: it's not.
Temporary super-intelligence
is just a side effect of the
Mega seeds dissolving
in your rectal cavity.
Aw, man.
Yeah, and once those
seeds [BURPS] wear off,
you're gonna lose
most of your motor skills,
and you're also gonna
lose a significant amount of
brain functionality for 72 hours, Morty.
Starting [BURPS] right about now.
Ohh, man.
[GROANING] Oh, jeez! Ohh.
I'm sorry, Morty. It's a bummer.
In reality, you're as dumb as they come.
And I needed those seeds real bad,
and I had to give them up just
to get your parents off my back,
so now we're gonna have to go get more.
And then we're gonna go on
even more adventures after that,
Morty.
And you're gonna keep your
mouth shut about it, Morty,
because the world is full of
idiots that don't understand
what's important,
and they'll tear us apart, Morty.
But if you stick with me, I'm
gonna accomplish great things,
Morty, and you're gonna
be part of them, and together,
we're gonna run around, Morty.
We're gonna do all kinds
of wonderful things, Morty.
Just you and me, Morty.
Oh, no, no.
The outside world is our enemy, Morty.
We're the only [BURPS]
friends we've got, Morty.
It's just Rick and Morty…
[BURPS] Rick and Morty
and their adventures, Morty.
Rick and Morty forever and forever.
A hundred years, Rick and Morty's things.
Me and Rick and Morty running
around, and Rick and Morty time.
All day long, forever.
All… a hundred days.
Rick and Morty forever… 100 times.
Over and over,
rickandmortyadventures.com.
www.rickandmorty.com.
www.rickandmortyadventures.
All 100 years.
Every minute, rickandmorty.com.
www.100timesrickandmorty.com.
MAN [ITALIAN ACCENT]: It's a good-a show!